<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Fellow A on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</title>
    <link>/authors/research-fellow-a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Fellow A on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/authors/research-fellow-a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s Regional Role</title>
      <link>/research/pakistans-regional-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/pakistans-regional-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;strategic-alignment-under-pressure&#34;&gt;Strategic Alignment Under Pressure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan’s foreign policy faces crosscutting demands: deepening ties with China through CPEC, rebalancing security cooperation with the United States, and managing expectations from Gulf partners. SIPEG analysis maps the institutional drivers of these choices and their implications for strategic autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;regional-platforms-and-multilateral-leverage&#34;&gt;Regional Platforms and Multilateral Leverage&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islamabad’s engagement with forums such as SCO, ECO, and ASEAN dialogues underscores a pragmatic search for diversified avenues of economic diplomacy. Our field interviews illustrate how bureaucratic capacity and private sector partnerships can unlock greater benefits from these alignments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Climate Adaptation in Pakistan’s Peripheries</title>
      <link>/research/financing-climate-adaptation-in-pakistans-peripheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/financing-climate-adaptation-in-pakistans-peripheries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pakistan’s frontline districts face escalating climate impacts without commensurate financing. This paper evaluates blended finance structures and district-level absorption capacity, identifying regulatory reforms that can unlock concessional capital.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key findings underscore the need for resilient infrastructure pipelines, climate-smart agriculture investments, and localized monitoring frameworks that build trust with funders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
