<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saeed Shafqat on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/saeed-shafqat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saeed Shafqat on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:50:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/saeed-shafqat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Official Islam to Islamism: The Rise of Dawat-ul-Irshad and Lashkar-e-Taiba</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/research/from-official-islam-to-islamism-the-rise-of-dawat-ul-irshad-and-lashkar-e-taiba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/research/from-official-islam-to-islamism-the-rise-of-dawat-ul-irshad-and-lashkar-e-taiba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study on Islam and Nationalism in Pakistan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study ventures to highlight the relation between Islam and nationalism in Pakistan. These two notions may appear self-contradictory since Islam transcends the frontiers of nation-states, including Pakistan. At the same time, the ideology of Pakistan has been built on the basis of the Muslim identity of the followers of Islam inhabiting the territories of British India. This paradox is even more evident from the discourse of the Islamist groups which are gaining momentum in Pakistan, especially in Punjab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAKISTAN: MILITANCY, THE TRANSITION TO DEMOCRACY AND FUTURE RELATIONS WITH THE UNITED STATES</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/research/pakistan-militancy-the-transition-to-democracy-and-future-relations-with-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/research/pakistan-militancy-the-transition-to-democracy-and-future-relations-with-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pakistan’s geostrategic location has made it a country of pivotal importance from the Cold War to the present day. Geography not only shapes Pakistan’s foreign policy, but also its defense considerations and strategic outlook. Its crucial position in South Asia, with its proximity to the Arabian Peninsula and access to the Horn of Africa and Central Asia, make it a strategically attractive and unavoidable state for global and regional powers. China continues to be a reliable friend and considers Pakistan a window of strategic opportunity.¹ For Russia, Pakistan could offer access to “warm waters” if Afghanistan were to gain stability, thus improving the level of trust between the two nations. India’s imminent emergence as a regional power will likely be contested by Pakistan, and the peace process between the two rivals will continue at a snail’s pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pluralist Society and Civic Responsibility in Pakistan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/research/pluralist-society-and-civic-responsibility-in-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/research/pluralist-society-and-civic-responsibility-in-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This&#x9;paper&#x9;is&#x9;divided&#x9;into&#x9; four&#x9;parts.&#x9; In&#x9; the&#x9; first&#x9;part,&#x9; I&#x9;would&#x9;like&#x9; to&#x9;provide&#x9;a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;conceptual&#x9; framework&#x9; of&#x9; the&#x9; Pluralist&#x9; Society&#x9; and&#x9; its&#x9; key&#x9; components.&#x9; In&#x9; the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;second&#x9; part&#x9; I&#x9; will&#x9; examine,&#x9; analyse&#x9; and&#x9; contend&#x9; that&#x9; Pakistan&#x9; was&#x9; born&#x9; as&#x9; a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pluralist&#x9;Society&#x9;and&#x9;in&#x9; reality&#x9; continues&#x9; to&#x9; be&#x9; vibrant&#x9;and&#x9; diverse&amp;ndash;&#x9;ethnically,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;linguistically,&#x9;culturally&#x9;and&#x9;in&#x9; terms&#x9;of&#x9;understanding&#x9;of&#x9;all&#x9; these&#x9;aspects.&#x9;&#x9;Yet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;over&#x9;the&#x9;decades,&#x9;security&#x9;imperatives&#x9;of&#x9;the&#x9;State&#x9;and&#x9;the&#x9;governing&#x9;elites&#x9;have&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
