<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</title>
    <link>/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on SIPEG — Shafqat Institute for Pakistan &amp; Emerging Geopolitics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pathways to Governance and Civil Service Reform in Pakistan: Federal, Provincial andLocal</title>
      <link>/research/pathways-to-governance-and-civil-service-reform-in-pakistan-federal-provincial-andlocal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/pathways-to-governance-and-civil-service-reform-in-pakistan-federal-provincial-andlocal/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this research is to provide a framework for dialogue on the concept of&#xA;governance and issues of civil service reform in Pakistan in general, and the Provinces in&#xA;particular. Governance and reform issues still remain peripheral and call for urgent attention. The remedy lies in a synergized top down and bottom up approach that may&#xA;be pursued to induce behavioral and structural change. So the paper, therefore&#xA;argues that, following the implementation of the 18th Amendment, provincial and&#xA;local governments should be the pivot for improving governance and pushing the&#xA;long overdue civil service reform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity, Governance, and Social Cohesion</title>
      <link>/research/identity-governance-and-social-cohesion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/identity-governance-and-social-cohesion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;evolving-narratives&#34;&gt;Evolving Narratives&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through archival analysis and contemporary discourse mapping, SIPEG researchers trace how identity frames influence public expectations of the state. The study highlights points of convergence between civic nationalism and faith-based narratives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;institutional-pathways&#34;&gt;Institutional Pathways&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reform initiatives require deliberate alignment across federal, provincial, and local institutions. Case studies from Punjab and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa reveal how administrative experimentation is reshaping citizen engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;implications-for-cohesion&#34;&gt;Implications for Cohesion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investing in inclusive curricula, digital public services, and open data transparency can dilute ethno-sectarian polarization while reinforcing trust in governance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
